<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/A-Thousand-Brains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/A-Thousand-Brains/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Neuroscience]]
[[Jeff Hawkins]]
[Chapter 1]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Books/</guid><description>Books Overview 1 type: folder_brief_live</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Consciousness-Christof-Koch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Consciousness-Christof-Koch/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Neuroscience]]
Consciousness: Confessions of a Romantic Reductionist [[Christof Koch]]
Chapter 1:
In philosophy, the difficulty of explaining why somebody can feel anything is often referred to as the Hard Problem. The term was coined by the philosopher David Chalmers.
Man must at last wake up out of his millenary dream and discover his total solitude, his fundamental isolation. He must realize that, like a gypsy, he lives on the boundary of an alien world; a world that is deaf to his music, and as indifferent to his hopes as it is to his sufferings and his crimes.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Dynamic-Field-Theory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Dynamic-Field-Theory/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Neuroscience]]
Dynamic Thinking: A Primer on Dynamic Field Theory Foundations of Dynamic Field Theory Introduction Provides neural process accounts for a large swath of behaviors and cognitive abilities History of Ideas Roots in motor/muscle control theory Stability is N&amp;amp;S for coordination patterns Can cognition arise directly from action-perception in closed loop Representational states Biological models do give rise to DFT dynamics DFT valid all the way from motor behavior to higher cognition Integration: follow common principles Chapter 1 Foundations [[Braitenberg Vehicle]] - neural account of behavior Sensors, effectors, nervous systems, bodies !</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/How-to-Win-Friends-and-Influence-People/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/How-to-Win-Friends-and-Influence-People/</guid><description>How to Win Friends and Influence People [[Dale Carnegie]]
Principles People crave the feeling of importance. Make someone feel important and they will think well of you. Diminish someone’s importance and they will resent you. Appeal to the other person’s interests. Virtually all people care more about what they want than what you want. You wouldn’t go fishing with cheesecake as a lure, since fish don’t like cheesecake. Go fishing with worms.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Neural-Engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Neural-Engineering/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Research]] [[Neuromorphic]]
Neural Engineering [[Chris Eliasmith]]
The 3 Principles Non-linear encoding + weighted linear decoding Transofrmations -&amp;gt; functions of variables represented by the population Dynamics -&amp;gt; representations as state variables Lots of noise System Description Interconnectivity Response functions Tuning curves (activity vs. input) Subsystem functional relations Overall behavior Design Specification Explicit operating conditions Noise, bandwidth, encoding, neuron number, SNR etc. Temporal, dynamic characteristics Implementation Determine decoding rules, weights Determine degree of detail for simulation Numerical experiments Representation Peripheral neuron -&amp;gt; dendritic tree: physical var.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Novacene/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Novacene/</guid><description>[[Books]]
Novacene [[James Lovelock]] [[Climate Change]][[Artificial Intelligence]][[Physics]] The effective temperature of the Earth when seen from outer space is hotter, not cooler, than Venus. I think the zone of habitability idea is flawed because it ignores the possibility that a planet bearing life will tend to modify its environment and climate in a way that favours the life upon it, as ours does.
A main sequence star like our Sun gradually heats the planet Daisyworld until it is just warm enough for a species of black daisies to colonize the entire surface.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Skyward_Series/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Skyward_Series/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Brandon Sanderson]]
Skyward Two. I felt, more than saw, the blossom of the bomb’s first explosion behind. And I felt, more than heard, M-Bot’s diagnostic tool working. “Biological component engaged,” his voice said. One. “Cytonic hyperdrive: online.” An explosion of fire surrounding us. “What?” M-Bot said. “Spin! Engage the—” I did something with my mind. We vanished, leaving a ship-size hole in the expanding blossom of flame and destruction.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Stormlight-Archive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Stormlight-Archive/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Brandon Sanderson]]
Some men, as they age, grow kinder. I am not one of those, for I have seen how the cosmere can mistreat the innocent - and that leaves me disinclined toward kindness. Some men, as they age, grow wiser. I am not one of those, for wisdom and I have always been cross-purposes, and I have yet to learn the tongue in which she speaks. Some men, as they age, grow more cynical.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/The-Human-Advantage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/The-Human-Advantage/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Neuroscience]]
The Human Advantage [[Suzanna Herculano-Houzel]] [[Neuroscience]]
That our brain outranks that of other animals not because we are an exception in evolution, but rather because, for simple evolutionary reasons, we hold the largest number of neurons in the cerebral cortex, affordable to no other species.
In terms of anatomy, our brain matter seemed to be made not very differently from that of other animals.
In our first analysis,3 which did not include the human brain, we found that brain mass in primates scales (increases) with the number of neurons in the brain raised to the power of +1.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Three-Body-Problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Three-Body-Problem/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Philosophy]] [[Metaphysics]] [[Science Fiction]]
In the shooter hypothesis, a good marksman shoots at a target, creating a hole every ten centimeters. Now suppose the surface of the target is inhabited by intelligent, two-dimensional creatures. Their scientists, after observing the universe, discover a great law: “There exists a hole in the universe every ten centimeters.” They have mistaken the result of the marksman’s momentary whim for an unalterable law of the universe.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/GM/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/GM/</guid><description>The Aravan Thing According to legend, Aravan is one of Arjuna’s sons. To ensure victory for the Pandavas, he offers to sacrifice his life. In return, he asks for three boons. He wants to die a hero’s death during battle; he wants to watch the entire battle, even after death; and he wants to experience marital bliss. The first two boons are easy to grant: he will be honourably beheaded and his severed head will oversee the war.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/HS5930-War-and-Peace-in-West-Asia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/HS5930-War-and-Peace-in-West-Asia/</guid><description>[[World]] [[West Asia]]
Feb 15 - Intro Class Middle East vs. West Asia naming convention - power dynamics Power shift to USA from Europe - Middle East popular Feb 16 - Background Deserts - influence on Islamic culture Connects 3 continents - strategic importance Birthplace of the 3 Abrahamic religions Oil Reserves Curse of the plenty Sustains deficit of democracy in the region [[Suez Canal]] boosted importance Known as Canaan in the Bible (Levant) Canaanites moved to lower Egypt for Nile Foreign (Hyskos) dynasty 13 Egypt UNO reversed and captured Canaan, turned into satellite state [[Etymology]] of [[Israel]]: Pharaoh named a city - Israel stelle - sometime in the Bronze Age (1265-1100 BCE) Iron Age : 1100 - 900 BCE Feb 18 - Origins of Islam Prophet Abraham established monotheistic understanding [[Jerusalem]], Temple Mount, Dome of the Rock is the cause of conflict Wailing wall for [[Jews]] 6 days of creation - 7th rest day Saturday/Sabbath for Jews Friday for Muslims Sunday for Christians Feb 22 - [[Prophet Muhammad]] Al-Miraj, the journey of Muhammad from Mecca-Jerusalem-Heaven 5 Pillars of Islam Only one god 5 prayers per day, reduced from 50 after Muhammad begged Giving alms Fasting during Ramzan Pilgrimage to [[Mecca]], Hajj Jahiliya: Days of ignorance, prior to rise of Islam Jericho: Oldest surviving human settlement, Ariha Quraysh: Pagan tribes Muhammad was born into, constructed Qabba Hijra Mhmd leaves Mecca after death of uncle Abu-Talib who was protecting him, out of fear Goes to Medina, along with followers, in 622 CE, the start of the Islamic calendar Also term used by Jinnah to refer to partition Came back to Mecca in 630 CE, died in 632 CE Removed idols from Qabba Offered amnesty to all Meccans, against advisors' suggestions, strengthened Islam in the process Erased distinction between: Ajami: Literally, dumb.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/config/</guid><description>Configuration Quartz is designed to be extremely configurable. You can find the bulk of the configuration scattered throughout the repository depending on how in-depth you&amp;rsquo;d like to get.
The majority of configuration can be be found under data/config.yaml. An annotated example configuration is shown below.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 name:Your name here!# Shows in the footerenableToc:true# Whether to show a Table of Contentsdescription:Page description to show to search enginespage_title:Quartz Example Page# Default Page Titlelinks:# Links to show in footer- link_name:Twitterlink:https://twitter.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Quartz to the Web</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/hosting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/hosting/</guid><description>GitHub Pages Quartz is designed to be effortless to deploy. If you forked and cloned Quartz directly from the repository, everything should already be good to go! You can head to &amp;lt;YOUR-GITHUB-USERNAME.github.io/quartz to see it live.
Enable GitHub Actions By default, GitHub disables workflows from running automatically on Forked Repostories. Head to the &amp;lsquo;Actions&amp;rsquo; tab of your forked repository and Enable Workflows to setup deploying your Quartz site!
Enable GitHub Actions</description></item><item><title>Editing Content in Quartz</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/editing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/editing/</guid><description>Editing Quartz runs on top of Hugo so all notes are written in Markdown .
Obsidian I strongly recommend using Obsidian as a way to edit and grow your digital garden. It comes with a really nice editor and graphical interface to preview all of my local files.
🔗 How to link your Obsidian Vault
Of course, all the files are in Markdown so you could just use your favourite text editor of choice.</description></item><item><title>External Hosting</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/external-hosting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/external-hosting/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ignoring Notes</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/ignore-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/ignore-notes/</guid><description>Quartz Ignore Edit ignoreFiles in config.toml to include paths you&amp;rsquo;d like to exclude from being rendered.
1 2 3 4 5 6 ... ignoreFiles = [ &amp;#34;/content/templates/*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;/content/private/*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;&amp;lt;your path here&amp;gt;&amp;#34; ] ignoreFiles supports the use of Regular Expressions (RegEx) so you can ignore patterns as well (e.g. ignoring all .pngs by doing \\.png$).
More details in Hugo&amp;rsquo;s documentation .
Global Ignore However, just adding to the ignoreFiles will only prevent the page from being access through Quartz.</description></item><item><title>Obsidian Vault Integration</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/obsidian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/obsidian/</guid><description>Setup Obsidian is the preferred way to use Quartz. You can either create a new Obsidian Vault or link one that your already have.
New Vault If you don&amp;rsquo;t have an existing Vault, download Obsidian and create a new Vault in the /content folder that you created and cloned during the setup .
Linking an existing Vault The easiest way to use an existing Vault is to copy all of our files (directory and hierarchies intact) into the /content folder.</description></item><item><title>Preview Changes</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/preview-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/preview-changes/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;d like to preview what your Quartz site looks like before deploying it to the internet, here&amp;rsquo;s exactly how to do that!
Install hugo-obsidian This step will generate the list of backlinks for Hugo to parse. Ensure you have Go (&amp;gt;= 1.16) installed.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 # Install and link `hugo-obsidian` locally $ go install github.com/jackyzha0/hugo-obsidian # Navigate to your local Quartz folder $ cd &amp;lt;location-of-your-local-quartz&amp;gt; # Scrape all links in your Quartz folder and generate info for Quartz $ hugo-obsidian -input=content -output=data Afterwards, start the Hugo server as shown above and your local backlinks and interactive graph should be populated!</description></item><item><title>Quartz Documentation</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/directory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/directory/</guid><description>Setup Welcome to Quartz! Whether you&amp;rsquo;re setting up a website and project for the first time or a seasoned digital gardener, I hope that you&amp;rsquo;ll find something useful about this project.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get to business and get you started!
📚 Setup your own digital garden using Quartz 🔗 Linking with an Obsidian Vault 🎨 Customizing and Styling Quartz 🌍 Hosting Quartz online! Not convinced yet?</description></item><item><title>Setup</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/setup/</guid><description>Making your own Quartz Setting up Quartz requires a basic understanding of git. If you are unfamiliar, this resource is a great place to start!
Forking A fork is a copy of a repository. Forking a repository allows you to freely experiment with changes without affecting the original project.
Navigate to the GitHub repository for the Quartz project:
📁 Quartz Repository Then, Fork the repository into your own GitHub account.</description></item><item><title>Showcase</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/showcase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/showcase/</guid><description>Want to see what Quartz can do? Here are some cool community gardens :)
Quartz Documentation (this site!) Strengthening Online Social Bonds: Research Garden Jacky Zhao&amp;rsquo;s Garden Anson Yu&amp;rsquo;s Garden Shihyu&amp;rsquo;s PKM Chloe&amp;rsquo;s Garden If you want to see your own on here, submit a Pull Request adding yourself to this file !</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting and FAQ</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/troubleshooting/</guid><description>Common Pitfalls Can I publish only a subset of my pages? Yes! Quartz makes selective publishing really easy. Heres a guide on excluding pages from being published .
Can I host this myself and not on GitHub Pages? Yes! All built files can be found under /public in the master branch. More details under hosting .
Do I need a website already? No! Setting up Quartz means you set up a site too :)</description></item></channel></rss>