<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/A-Thousand-Brains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/A-Thousand-Brains/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Neuroscience]]
[[Jeff Hawkins]]
[Chapter 1]</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Books/</guid><description>Books Overview 1 type: folder_brief_live</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Consciousness-Christof-Koch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Consciousness-Christof-Koch/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Neuroscience]]
Consciousness: Confessions of a Romantic Reductionist [[Christof Koch]]
Chapter 1:
In philosophy, the difficulty of explaining why somebody can feel anything is often referred to as the Hard Problem. The term was coined by the philosopher David Chalmers.
Man must at last wake up out of his millenary dream and discover his total solitude, his fundamental isolation. He must realize that, like a gypsy, he lives on the boundary of an alien world; a world that is deaf to his music, and as indifferent to his hopes as it is to his sufferings and his crimes.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Dynamic-Field-Theory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Dynamic-Field-Theory/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Neuroscience]]
Dynamic Thinking: A Primer on Dynamic Field Theory Foundations of Dynamic Field Theory Introduction Provides neural process accounts for a large swath of behaviors and cognitive abilities History of Ideas Roots in motor/muscle control theory Stability is N&amp;amp;S for coordination patterns Can cognition arise directly from action-perception in closed loop Representational states Biological models do give rise to DFT dynamics DFT valid all the way from motor behavior to higher cognition Integration: follow common principles Chapter 1 Foundations [[Braitenberg Vehicle]] - neural account of behavior Sensors, effectors, nervous systems, bodies !</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/How-to-Win-Friends-and-Influence-People/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/How-to-Win-Friends-and-Influence-People/</guid><description>How to Win Friends and Influence People [[Dale Carnegie]]
Principles People crave the feeling of importance. Make someone feel important and they will think well of you. Diminish someone’s importance and they will resent you. Appeal to the other person’s interests. Virtually all people care more about what they want than what you want. You wouldn’t go fishing with cheesecake as a lure, since fish don’t like cheesecake. Go fishing with worms.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Neural-Engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Neural-Engineering/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Research]] [[Neuromorphic]]
Neural Engineering [[Chris Eliasmith]]
The 3 Principles Non-linear encoding + weighted linear decoding Transofrmations -&amp;gt; functions of variables represented by the population Dynamics -&amp;gt; representations as state variables Lots of noise System Description Interconnectivity Response functions Tuning curves (activity vs. input) Subsystem functional relations Overall behavior Design Specification Explicit operating conditions Noise, bandwidth, encoding, neuron number, SNR etc. Temporal, dynamic characteristics Implementation Determine decoding rules, weights Determine degree of detail for simulation Numerical experiments Representation Peripheral neuron -&amp;gt; dendritic tree: physical var.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Novacene/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Novacene/</guid><description>[[Books]]
Novacene [[James Lovelock]] [[Climate Change]][[Artificial Intelligence]][[Physics]] The effective temperature of the Earth when seen from outer space is hotter, not cooler, than Venus. I think the zone of habitability idea is flawed because it ignores the possibility that a planet bearing life will tend to modify its environment and climate in a way that favours the life upon it, as ours does.
A main sequence star like our Sun gradually heats the planet Daisyworld until it is just warm enough for a species of black daisies to colonize the entire surface.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Skyward_Series/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Skyward_Series/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Brandon Sanderson]]
Skyward Two. I felt, more than saw, the blossom of the bomb’s first explosion behind. And I felt, more than heard, M-Bot’s diagnostic tool working. “Biological component engaged,” his voice said. One. “Cytonic hyperdrive: online.” An explosion of fire surrounding us. “What?” M-Bot said. “Spin! Engage the—” I did something with my mind. We vanished, leaving a ship-size hole in the expanding blossom of flame and destruction.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Stormlight-Archive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Stormlight-Archive/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Brandon Sanderson]]
Some men, as they age, grow kinder. I am not one of those, for I have seen how the cosmere can mistreat the innocent - and that leaves me disinclined toward kindness. Some men, as they age, grow wiser. I am not one of those, for wisdom and I have always been cross-purposes, and I have yet to learn the tongue in which she speaks. Some men, as they age, grow more cynical.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/The-Human-Advantage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/The-Human-Advantage/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Neuroscience]]
The Human Advantage [[Suzanna Herculano-Houzel]] [[Neuroscience]]
That our brain outranks that of other animals not because we are an exception in evolution, but rather because, for simple evolutionary reasons, we hold the largest number of neurons in the cerebral cortex, affordable to no other species.
In terms of anatomy, our brain matter seemed to be made not very differently from that of other animals.
In our first analysis,3 which did not include the human brain, we found that brain mass in primates scales (increases) with the number of neurons in the brain raised to the power of +1.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Three-Body-Problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/Books/Three-Body-Problem/</guid><description>[[Books]] [[Philosophy]] [[Metaphysics]] [[Science Fiction]]
In the shooter hypothesis, a good marksman shoots at a target, creating a hole every ten centimeters. Now suppose the surface of the target is inhabited by intelligent, two-dimensional creatures. Their scientists, after observing the universe, discover a great law: “There exists a hole in the universe every ten centimeters.” They have mistaken the result of the marksman’s momentary whim for an unalterable law of the universe.</description></item></channel></rss>