<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mocs on</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/</link><description>Recent content in Mocs on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/GM/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/GM/</guid><description>The Aravan Thing According to legend, Aravan is one of Arjuna’s sons. To ensure victory for the Pandavas, he offers to sacrifice his life. In return, he asks for three boons. He wants to die a hero’s death during battle; he wants to watch the entire battle, even after death; and he wants to experience marital bliss. The first two boons are easy to grant: he will be honourably beheaded and his severed head will oversee the war.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/HS5930-War-and-Peace-in-West-Asia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/HS5930-War-and-Peace-in-West-Asia/</guid><description>[[World]] [[West Asia]]
Feb 15 - Intro Class Middle East vs. West Asia naming convention - power dynamics Power shift to USA from Europe - Middle East popular Feb 16 - Background Deserts - influence on Islamic culture Connects 3 continents - strategic importance Birthplace of the 3 Abrahamic religions Oil Reserves Curse of the plenty Sustains deficit of democracy in the region [[Suez Canal]] boosted importance Known as Canaan in the Bible (Levant) Canaanites moved to lower Egypt for Nile Foreign (Hyskos) dynasty 13 Egypt UNO reversed and captured Canaan, turned into satellite state [[Etymology]] of [[Israel]]: Pharaoh named a city - Israel stelle - sometime in the Bronze Age (1265-1100 BCE) Iron Age : 1100 - 900 BCE Feb 18 - Origins of Islam Prophet Abraham established monotheistic understanding [[Jerusalem]], Temple Mount, Dome of the Rock is the cause of conflict Wailing wall for [[Jews]] 6 days of creation - 7th rest day Saturday/Sabbath for Jews Friday for Muslims Sunday for Christians Feb 22 - [[Prophet Muhammad]] Al-Miraj, the journey of Muhammad from Mecca-Jerusalem-Heaven 5 Pillars of Islam Only one god 5 prayers per day, reduced from 50 after Muhammad begged Giving alms Fasting during Ramzan Pilgrimage to [[Mecca]], Hajj Jahiliya: Days of ignorance, prior to rise of Islam Jericho: Oldest surviving human settlement, Ariha Quraysh: Pagan tribes Muhammad was born into, constructed Qabba Hijra Mhmd leaves Mecca after death of uncle Abu-Talib who was protecting him, out of fear Goes to Medina, along with followers, in 622 CE, the start of the Islamic calendar Also term used by Jinnah to refer to partition Came back to Mecca in 630 CE, died in 632 CE Removed idols from Qabba Offered amnesty to all Meccans, against advisors' suggestions, strengthened Islam in the process Erased distinction between: Ajami: Literally, dumb.</description></item><item><title>Quartz Documentation</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/directory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/directory/</guid><description>Setup Welcome to Quartz! Whether you&amp;rsquo;re setting up a website and project for the first time or a seasoned digital gardener, I hope that you&amp;rsquo;ll find something useful about this project.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get to business and get you started!
📚 Setup your own digital garden using Quartz 🔗 Linking with an Obsidian Vault 🎨 Customizing and Styling Quartz 🌍 Hosting Quartz online! Not convinced yet?</description></item><item><title>Showcase</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/showcase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/moc/showcase/</guid><description>Want to see what Quartz can do? Here are some cool community gardens :)
Quartz Documentation (this site!) Strengthening Online Social Bonds: Research Garden Jacky Zhao&amp;rsquo;s Garden Anson Yu&amp;rsquo;s Garden Shihyu&amp;rsquo;s PKM Chloe&amp;rsquo;s Garden If you want to see your own on here, submit a Pull Request adding yourself to this file !</description></item></channel></rss>